<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>whoami on Chaos &amp; Void</title><link>https://misterbianco.github.io/</link><description>Recent content in whoami on Chaos &amp; Void</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://misterbianco.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Software Complexity Pt 1</title><link>https://misterbianco.github.io/posts/complexity_1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://misterbianco.github.io/posts/complexity_1/</guid><description>Why is software development so complex? I was asked a variation of this question by a coworker this week, and he wanted a one sentence answer.
After pondering for a bit I said:
Marrying experience and assumptions of engineers to reality is a non-trivial task.
I firmly believe this to be true. However, I can&amp;rsquo;t boil down the problem to such a small pithy value statement and pretend it addresses the entirety of the issue.</description></item><item><title>Culture Shifting</title><link>https://misterbianco.github.io/posts/culture/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2020 03:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://misterbianco.github.io/posts/culture/</guid><description>The process of shifting a culture This subject has so much literature that it may seem arrogant to think myself in any way qualified to write on culture. While there are certainly smarter people leaders, thinkers and engineers than I who have tackled this issue, I hope to throw my own thoughts into the polluted pool and see what sticks.
Entering the realm of opinion
Identifying the current culture I have worked at different outfits that have each spoken of their culture using pithy and abstract values like &amp;ldquo;honesty&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;courage&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;integrity&amp;rdquo; and while I am glad a C level executive is pleased with his work defining his companies 5-13 core principles/values/belief etc.</description></item><item><title>Docs as code</title><link>https://misterbianco.github.io/posts/docs/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2020 02:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://misterbianco.github.io/posts/docs/</guid><description>Prologue If you haven&amp;rsquo;t read my previous article about wikis you can do so here
Documentation as code There is hopefully a fairly obvious pattern in my posts, I am a religious believer in everything as code. This is just the next installation in that series.
Documentation as code is the idea that documentation should be kept close to the code and highly visible. If you want to generate documentation for a project you can use a documentation generation tool provided by the language like nim&amp;rsquo;s nimdoc tool, pythons mkdoc or sphinx, and there are others or you can use a static site generator like hugo or zola.</description></item><item><title>Wikis aren't for humans</title><link>https://misterbianco.github.io/posts/wiki/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2020 01:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://misterbianco.github.io/posts/wiki/</guid><description>Wiki&amp;rsquo;s where knowledge goes to die I work at a company that makes use of confluent for wiki articles and I get told a lot when I ask questions that I need to &amp;ldquo;go read the wiki.&amp;rdquo; Which causes a sense of dread because when I search for information in the wiki I get the following:
Search: pipeline webhook token Results:
ngp pipelines ngp fargate pipelines ngp v2 pipelines ngp pipeline - other pipelines in aws monorepo pipelines pipelines for polyrepos sonarqube in a monorepo inside a polyrepo in a mini repo in space Which of these could possibly be the correct article?</description></item><item><title>Bringing ADR's to my company</title><link>https://misterbianco.github.io/posts/adr/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://misterbianco.github.io/posts/adr/</guid><description>Bringing ADR&amp;rsquo;s to WGU Firstly, the context necessary to understand this post and the benefits of ADR&amp;rsquo;s (architectural design records) can be found here.
There are moments in every engineers career where they look at a codebase either as a newcomer or as a seasoned vet of that repo and they go, &amp;ldquo;why did we do X.&amp;rdquo; The more pervasive this issue this is the more you will benefit from ADR&amp;rsquo;s.</description></item></channel></rss>